Finding Aid for Presidential Inaugurations (University of Michigan) Records, 1920-2003
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Presidential Inaugurations (University of Michigan) records 1920- 2003
University of Michigan. Presidential Inaugurations.
2.5 linear feet, and one outsize folder
0647 Bimu 2
Materials related to the inaugurations of University of Michigan presidents, including Marion Leroy Burton (1920), Robben Fleming (1968), Harold T. Shapiro (1980) and Mary Sue Coleman (2003).
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Received from multiple sources and campus offices. Donor numbers 566, 1278, 4564, 4642, 5670.
The records are open without restriction.
The Presidential Inaugurations recod group was assembled from a variety of sources and donors.
This collection is arranged into four series, one for each University President represented: Marion Leroy Burton, 1920, Robben Fleming, 1968, Harold T. Shapiro, 1980 and Mary Sue Coleman, 2003. Although the contents of each series vary slightly, they generally contain planning materials, lists of invitees and/or guests, correspondence, and ceremonial greetings and certificates sent by other universities. The two latest series also include audiovisual recordings.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. President.; Burton, Marion Le Roy, 1874-1925.; Fleming, R. W. (Robben Wright), 1916-; Shapiro, Harold T., 1935-; Coleman, Mary Sue.
Genre Terms:
Videotapes.; DVDs.
- Marion Leroy Burton, 1920
  - Registration Book of Delegates and Guests (Box 1)
  - Exhibits (Box 1)
  - Hospitality Committee
    - Correspondence (Box 1)
    - Reports on Educational Conference, with exhibits (Box 1)
  - Proceedings of Deans’ Committee (Box 1)
  - Delegates List (Box 1)
  - Selected Replies to Invitations (Box 1)
  - Correspondence and Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Printed Materials, Seating Charts and Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Robben Fleming, 1968
  - Congratulatory Letters and RSVPs, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Greetings and Certificates, 5 folders and items in outsize folder (Box 1)
  - Invitations and Programs Samples (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Work Material, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Agenda and Address (Box 1)
- Harod T. Shapiro, 1980
  - Plans for Inaugural Ceremony (Box 2)
  - Inaugural Committee Miscellany (Box 2)
  - Activities (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Invitations and Programs Samples (Box 2)
  - Regrets to Invitations (Box 2)
  - Correspondence (Box 2)
  - Tape of Luncheon Speech by Sara Power, 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2)
  - Congratulatory Letters (Box 2)
  - Certificates, 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Guest List (Box 2)
  - Invitees (Box 2)
    (index card file)
  - Seating (Box 2)
  - Inauguration LXXX Wine (Box 2)
    (empty wine bottle)
- James J. Duderstadt, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Inauguration press packet, 1988
    (See also: President (University of Michigan) record group, James J. Duderstadt "Engagements" for ceremony, remarks, planning, congratulatory correspondence)
- Mary Sue Coleman, 2003
  - Greetings and Certificates (Box 3)
    (2 folders and items in outsize folder)
  - Invitations Samples (Box 3)
  - Invitees List (Box 3)
  - Program Script (Box 3)
  - Inauguration, DVD and 2 VHS videocassettes (Box 3)
  - Academic Symposium "For a University of the World", DVD and VHS videocassette (Box 3)
Related Material
Materials on the inauguration of other University of Michigan Presidents can be found in the following collections and record groups held by the Bentley Library:
Clarence Cook Little (1924): Clarence Cook Little papers
Harlan Hatcher (1951): Harlan Hatcher papers
James J. Duderstadt (1988):
James J. Duderstadt papers
President (University of Michigan) records
University and Development Events records
Lee C. Bollinger (1997): President (University of Michigan) records
For additional materials related to the inauguration of Robben Fleming (1968), see also Chief Marshal (University of Michigan) records and President (University of Michigan) records.